<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Timelapse IO]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.timelapse.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.timelapse.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-27T09:40:26+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.timelapse.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[James Broad]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi Time Lapse Camera]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.timelapse.io/blog/2013/03/26/raspberry-pi-time-lapse-camera/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-26T09:38:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.timelapse.io/blog/2013/03/26/raspberry-pi-time-lapse-camera</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe width="789" height="400" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/ClpkPL0hyZE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>I wanted to be able to capture photos as frequently as possible of myself to track my movements and ageing over time.</p>

<p>I have in the past created a daemon that ran on my laptop and took photos using the webcam and this worked great but only worked when the laptop was on and only captured my face.</p>

<p>That&#8217;s what spurred me on to get a Raspberry Pi with a high resolution webcam to allow me to stick it in the corner of the room and to start taking pictures which would generate and upload a daily <strong>time lapse</strong>.</p>

<!-- 
Here's how the humble device looks at present:

INSERT PHOTO OF PI
-->


<p>Behind the scenes it uses the fantastic <a href="http://www.lavrsen.dk/foswiki/bin/view/Motion/">motion</a> library which makes it a doddle to configure your device to regularly take photos and conveniently creates time lapse videos for you.</p>

<h2>Current Issues</h2>

<p>I keep facing problems with photos just not being captured, with nothing in the logs that indicate something going wrong. I suspect this is a memory (RAM) issue and will run a cron to clear out memory caches.</p>

<p>I am also facing issues uploading the time lapse videos created, this could be a number of things but seems to be with the motion library on_video_created event.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
